Artsiom Pchaliankou

Email / pchelenkovartem@gmail.com
Phone / 076-9612198
Location / Stockholm, SE





https://artempchelenkov.xyz/



I am a hard-working and self-motivated front-end developer with 2 years of experience. Currently at Swedcon18 AB, I have been working together with both designers and back-end developers using Javascript, React and NextJS + Docker mainly to develop the front-end part of the platform, writing documentation and onboarding juniors to the project.

I am a quick learner and easily adapt to new things. I enjoy working in a team and under pressure, as well as analyzing and solving problems. Currently I'm diving deeper into React and its ecosystem.

Skills

Front-end:

- HTML, CSS(sass/scss) / JavaScript / TypeScript / ReactJS / Tailwind / Bootstrap Back-end:
 - NodeJS / ExpressJS / NextJS / Prisma / PostgresQL

APIs:

REST APIs / useQuery / Fetch / Axios

Cloud Computing:

• Docker / AWS (Amplify, Route53, S3)

Version control:

· Git / GitHub

Experience

Swedcon18 AB - Front-end Developer (Stockholm) / 2021 - Current

I am working on an amazing project that will help people with low-income to improve their health. In this project I have been collaborating closely with both the designers and the back-end team while learning more about the back-end system that is built on Java and Spring Boot.

- Building the front-end platform using React, NextJS, Postman, Docker.
- · Mentor junior developers and onboard them to the project
- · Composing documentation about the technologies and our system in general.

Tech stack:

Javascript, ReactJS, NextJS, useQuery(tanstack), TypeScript, Axios, Tailwind, Module.(s)css, Docker, Github, Postman, CI/CD pipeline, Figma UI/UX designe

Spacept AB - Junior front-end Developer (Stockholm) / 2021 - 2021

I was a part of a small but very fast-growing startup Spacept AB for a 6 months project. In this company, I worked with a creative and fully energetic team. For this short work term I learned new techniques such as Amazon Web Services: Amplify, Route 53, Simple Storage Services (S3). As well as WordPress and FileZilla.

My main task was to create a calculator on the React.js library to compare different types of inspection. I worked with geolocation on automatic recognition of Euro and Dollar zones for different clients. This application is responsive and fully integrated into WP. You may check my work on the official website www.spacept.com

Tech stack:

Javascript, ReactJS, Axios, Module.(s)css, Docker, Github, Postman, CI/CD pipeline, NextJS, Figma

Education

Folkuniversitet / 2021-2022 English for work (B1, B2, C1)

STEP Academy / 2018 Front-end development

References



Artsiom is a skilled and dedicated frontend developer. Hime has a consistent workflow that makes him stand out. He's a good communicator and pays good attention to details and task requirements. He's a good friend and working with him is always fun and full of exciting.